We are infinite.
The Perks of Being a Wallflower is a drama film directed by Stephen Chbosky.
Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1991.
High school freshman Charlie is a wallflower, always watching life from the sidelines, until two senior students, Sam and
her stepbrother Patrick, become his mentors, helping him discover the joys of friendship, music and love.
Charlie, played by Logan Lerman.
Sam, played by Emma Watson.
Patrick, played by Ezra Miller.
Mary Elizabeth, played by Mae Whitman.
Mother, played by Kate Walsh.
Father, played by Dylan McDermott.
The Perks of Being a Wallflower is a 2012 American coming-of-age romantic drama film
written and directed by Stephen Chbosky, and based on his 1999 novel.
Logan Lerman stars as a teenager named Charlie who writes to an unnamed friend, and these epistles chronicle
his trials, tribulations, and triumphs as he goes through his freshman year of high school.
The film depicts his struggles with his, unbeknownst to him, post-traumatic stress disorder, as he goes
through his journey in high school making new friends, portrayed by Emma Watson and Ezra Miller.
The film's ensemble cast also includes Mae Whitman, Kate Walsh, Dylan
McDermott, Joan Cusack, Nina Dobrev, and Paul Rudd in supporting roles.
Chbosky had always intended to adapt the novel to
film, but did not rush to do so.
He was hesitant to sell the rights to the film to
anyone, but eventually sold them to Mr.
Mudd Productions as long as they let him write and direct the film.
Principal photography began in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, in
May 2011 and lasted approximately fifty days.
The Perks of Being a Wallflower had its world premiere at the 2012 Toronto
International Film Festival on September 8, 2012, to a standing ovation.
It was released theatrically in the United States on
September 21, 2012, by Summit Entertainment.
The film was well received by critics, who praised Chbosky's screenplay and direction, the performances
of Lerman, Watson and Miller, soundtrack, execution of its topics, and emotional weight.
It was also a box office success, grossing $33.3 million on a budget of $13 million, and received several accolades, including the Independent Spirit
Award for Best First Feature, two Critics' Choice Movie Awards nominations, and the GLAAD Media Award for Outstanding Film – Wide Release.
The film has since become a cult classic, especially among Zillennials,
and helped define the "Tumblr era" in the early 2010s.
The film explores themes of school friend, depression, high
school, friendship, based on novel or book.
The tone is emotional.